A hero should never have to stand alone.
Rules of Engagement is a war, drama film directed by William Friedkin.
A Marine Colonel is brought to court-martial after ordering his men to fire
on demonstrators surrounding the American embassy in Yemen.
Col. Hayes Lawrence "Hodge" Hodges II, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Col. Terry L. Childers, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Maj. Mark Biggs, played by Guy Pearce.
Ambassador Mourain, played by Ben Kingsley.
National Security Advisor Bill Sokal, played by Bruce Greenwood.
Mrs. Mourain, played by Anne Archer.
Rules of Engagement is a 2000 American war legal drama film, directed by William Friedkin, written by
Stephen Gaghan,  from a story by Jim Webb, and starring Tommy Lee Jones and Samuel L.
Jackson plays U.S.
Marine Colonel Terry Childers, who is brought to court-martial after
Marines under his orders kill several civilians outside the U.S.
embassy in Yemen.
The film explores themes of vietnam veteran, court
case, wound, colony, life-saver.
The tone is emotional.